Francesco Dondi

The guarantee of experience, the enthusiasm for good engineering.

Latest version of this CV at: github.com/Fdondi/cv-latex/blob/main/cv_en.pdf Zugerstarsse 66, 8810 Horgen, ZH \Box +41 76 456 50 32 ☑ francesco314@gmail.com in francesco-dondi ♠ Fdondi

> Born 29/10/1990 Italian citizen, C permit Married, no children



0000

0000

90000

90001

Who I am

As a seasoned software developer, I bring a wealth of experience in developing robust software solutions, optimizing SQL databases, and implementing effective data analytics. My expertise ranges from securing and improving server configurations to developing endto-end sophisticated software solutions. I'm known among my peers and supervisors for being a reliable, intelligent, and friendly colleague, one who is always ready to take on responsibility and contribute to the team's success.

Professional Experience

Winterthur Company size: 3

03/2023 - 09/2023

Zürich

Company size: 50

06/2021 - 09/2022

Zürich

Company size: 50

08/2020 - 02/2021

Zug

Company size: 5

10/2017 - 05/2020 Software Developer, Google

Company size: 100k

04/2016 - 10/2017 Luqa, Malta

Company size: 50

04/2015 - 04/2016 **Genua**, Italy Company size: 5

03/2024 - 05/2024 Software Developer, Deep Impact

Had the opportunity to have direct experience of Computer Vision, both on cloud and edge embedded devices (Nvidia Jetson platform). Contributed by overhauling Docker setup and solving bugs.

Software Developer, DoubleCloud

Maintained and developed the infrastructure around managed Click-House, in particular:

Secured metrics server by adding Nginx

Improved SaltStack configuration Solved bugs in Telegraf Go plugins

Software Developer, Firebolt

Maintained and developed the SQL optimization engine and testing infrastructure.

Expanded supported SQL syntax and optimizations
 reworked the test framework to support new test suite

o contributed to rewriting to higher standards the optimization engine

Developer / Analyst, **F-Trust**O Maintained and developed a Trading Engine (C++)

o redesigned, implemented and migrated storage (PostgreSQL)

extracted and integrated data from multiple log streams

analyzed data to highlight opportunities for improvement (Julia)

Within Search, productionized an initially experimental tool (C++). Improved runtime from days to hours

added support for new kinds of data

made the results easily visualizable and monitorable made onboarding orders of magnitude faster for most cases

Software Developer, Ascent Software

I helped maintain and develop a driver (C++) for automotive communications, running both on regular computers and embedded (QNX real-time OS) systems.

Junior Developer, Rulex Inc. /CNR

Explored options for speeding up C algorithms with CPU (OpenMP) and GPU (Nvidia CUDA) parallelization. Transported MATLAB algorithms to Python.

Skills

Programming

C++

- C++/Abseil

- C++/Boost

Java SQL

- Clickhouse SQL

- PostgreSQL

Python Julia

Go

Universal Tools

BASH Visual Studio

Git

Jenkins CI

Advanced Tools

Docker gRPC

ZeroMQ

Valgrind

Flamegraph Gstreamer

Nvidia CUDA

OpenMP

Platforms Linux

AWS

Windows

Nvidia Jetson

Competences

Testing Debugging DevOps

Design Docs Embedded Dev.

Agile Dev.

Languages

English Italiano Deutsch Français



Formal education

02/2024-10/2024 (exp.)	CAS ETH in Machine Learning in Finance and Insurance, ETH Zürich		
01/2023-06/2023	Business Analytics: From Data to Decisions, Imperial College Business School		
2009–2015	Galileian School of Higher Education, University of Padua, Enriching program, 98/100		
2012–2014	Master Degree in Mathematics, University of Padua, 108/110		
2009–2012	Bachelor Degree in Mathematics, University of Padua, 110/110 cum Laude		
2004–2009	High School - Science Track, added IT, French, Liceo Fermi, Bologna, 100/100 cum Laude		

Continuous Learning

Data Science/Analytics

Nov 2023	Linkedin	Data Fluency: Exploring and Describing Data	Data Analysis	
Nov 2023	Linkedin	Power BI Essential Training	Data Visualization	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Business Intelligence for Consultants	Probability	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Data Analytics for Business Professionals	Microsoft Power BI	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Excel: Economic Analysis and Data Analytics	Microsoft Excel	00000
Oct 2023	Linkedin	The Non-Technical Skills of Effective Data Scientists	Pandas	
		Machine Learning/LLMs/AI		
Jan 2024	Coursera	Generative AI with Large Language Models	LLMs	
		Programming languages		
Nov 2023	Linkedin	C# Essential Training 1: Types and Control Flow	C#	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Learning MATLAB	MATLAB	
		Embedded development		
Nov 2023	Linkedin	C Programming for Embedded Applications	C Embedded	
		Cloud and DevOps		
Feb 2023	Linkedin	AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA-C02)	Cloud Admin	••••
		Cert Prep: 1 Cloud Services Overview	AWS Cloud	
Jan 2023	Linkedin	DevOps Foundations: Going Cloud Native	DevOps	

Projects

Embedded



Nov 2023 **BTC** Arduino monitor

github.com/Fdondi/arduino-btc

Board blinking green for increased bitcoin pirce, red for decrease. Blinks faster for fast price change.

LLMs / Prompt engineering



Dec 2023

Deutsches Wörterbuch

chat.openai.com/g/g-bpvvdzIKE-deutsches-worterbuch

CustomGPT for grammar, explanation in German and English, examples. Clarifies ambiguous words. Adjusts German level.

Competitions

2009 Italian Olympics of Mathematics, Gold 🕯

2008 Italian Olympics of Information Technology, Bronze

12-13/12/15 **H-Farm**, *H-Ack Luxottica*, Ideas for the future of glasses.

19-20/03/16 **H-Farm**, *H-Ack Food*, Reinventing the 'Bio food' experience.

C++ Embedded Arduino

SSH embedded Embedded Development



AI UX Prompt engineering



Personal

Hobbies:

Read, hike, bike, swim.